live. Like I say, welcome brothers and
sisters to another Wednesday question
and answer where we open up with the 10
commandments that God had written for
the whole world to keep. Brother Tanzel,
and God spake all these words, saying, I
am the Lord thy God, which has brought
thee out of the land of Egypt, out of
the house of bondage. Thou shall have no
other gods before me. Thou shall not
make unto thee any graven image, or any
likeness of anything that is in heaven
above, or that is in the earth beneath,
or that is in the water under the earth.
Thou shall not bow down thou thyself to
them, nor serve them. For I the Lord thy
God am a jealous God, visiting the
iniquities of the fathers upon the
children, unto the third and fourth
generation of them that hate me, and
showing mercy unto thousands of them
that love me and keep my commandments.
Thou shalt not take the name of the Lord
thy God in vain. For the Lord will not
hold him guiltless that take of his name
in vain. Remember the Sabbath day to
keep it holy. Six days sh thy layman do
all thy work. But the seventh day is the
Sabbath of the Lord thy God. And thou
shall not do any work. Thou nor thy son,
nor thy daughter, thy man's servant, nor
thy maid servant, nor thy cattle, nor
that stranger that is within thy gates.
For six days the Lord made heaven and
earth, the sea, and all that in the
midst, and rested the seventh day.
Wherefore the Lord blessed the Sabbath
day, and hollowed it, honor thy father
and thy mother, that thy days may be
long upon the land which the Lord thy
God giveth thee. Thou shall not kill.
Thou shall not commit adultery. Thou
shall not steal. Thou shall not bear
false witness against thy neighbor. Thou
shall not coveret thy neighbor's house.
Thou shalt not cover thy neighbor's
wife, nor his man's servant, nor his
maid servant, nor his ox, nor his ass,
nor anything that is thy neighbors. We
read Exodus 21-17. And may the Lord have
a blessing to the reading of his words.
It's in Jesus name we pray. Amen. Amen.
Amen. So here on question and answer,
you can ask us a question and we'll
answer it according to the King James
Bible. And if we cannot find the answer,
we will seek further counsel to bring
you an answer at a later time. The
questions we will not answer are the
very long questions, the vague
questions, and the questions of debate.
We are not here to debate. We are here
to spread the true gospel of Jesus. So
please be as direct as possible with
your questions so we can be as direct as
possible with our answers out of the
King James Bible. No other Bibles or
books will be acknowledged on this
program. Also, keep in mind this is a
live stream. So, feel free to send in
your questions that pertain to
everlasting life. We just ask that you
keep them to a two scripture maximum.
Let me introduce to you the family
that's on the panel this evening.
Brother Dre, good evening. Brother
Julius, good evening everybody. Brother
Jerome, rest in peace. Brother Tanzel,
good evening. Sister Deborah, good
evening. Brother Sean, good evening. And
we have the guest caller with us. And
I'm brother Cornell. Sister Deborah,
what is our first question of the
evening? Yes, there are several held
over questions that will be answered
first before getting into tonight's Q&A.
So, uh, Mrs. way asked in 1 Corinthians
verse31. What did Paul mean when he said
he died daily?
Okay. What did Paul mean in that 1
Corinthians 15 and verse 31? Why don't
we go there, brother
Tenzel? And let's pick that
up at the 1 Corinthians
15 and 31.
Go ahead.
I protest by your rejoicing which I have
in Christ Jesus our Lord and I die
daily. So Paul is saying here that he
died daily which he is meaning that he
is killing that flesh every day. That
whenever that flesh rise up against him,
he had to kill it and walk in the
commandments of God like the Lord
commanded everybody to keep. And even
when you see people on this panel, we
also are killing that flesh daily so
that we may walk in the spirit of God.
And we'll read about that, too. Let's
turn over to Romans 7. Romans the 7th
chapter. And when you get to that Romans
7, let's pick it up at that verse
seven. Because when you walk in the law
of God, you are working on saving your
life. even forever more. Romans 7 and 7.
Go ahead. What shall we say then? Is the
law sin? God forbid. That's right.
Go ahead. But nay, I had not known sin
but by the law, but I had not known
lust, except the law had said, "Thou
shall not cover it."
Paul is letting us know that, hey, he
didn't know what lust meant until the
law came into effect in his mind and in
his heart and say, look, thou shalt not
lust. And then he said, oh, okay. Well,
thou shall not covet. And he stopped his
lusting. Go ahead.
But sin, taking occasion by the
commandment wroth in me all manner of
concupitence. For without the law, sin
was dead. And if you don't have the law
of the commandments, then you can do all
the sin you like. And we know that God
hates sin. So we know that that doesn't
match up. So you have to make sure
because without the law, hey, you do all
kind of unclean and things against God.
Verse nine. Well, I was alive without
the law once. But when the commandment
came, sin revived and I died. Oh, so he
say he was alive doing Hey, you can do
plenty of sin if there is no law. But
then Paul said that when that
commandment came and it taught him that
thou shall not steal, thou shall not
kill, thou shall not covet and all these
things and he was getting away from the
things of the flesh and putting on the
spirit of God. Turn over to Romans 8 and
let's see why he was doing that. Romans
8 and when you get there, pick it up at
that verse four. Romans 8 and four. Go
ahead. that the righteousness of the law
might be fulfilled in us who walk not
after the flesh but after the spirit.
And Paul knew that too, that he could
not be walking after the flesh, cuz as
we just read, they do all kind of things
contrary to God. You have to walk in the
spirit of God and put on his law. Read.
For they that are after the flesh do
mind the things of the flesh. But they
that are after the spirit the things of
the spirit. Yeah.
For to be connally minded is death, but
to be spiritually minded is life and
peace. So Lord say that hey in the
scripture for to be carnally minded is
death. To walk in that flesh and do all
the things like Paul say he was doing
early until that law came and changed
him. Hey, you are walking contrary to
God and you can also be walking in the
ways of death. Verse seven, because the
carnal mind is immity against God, for
it is not subject to the law of God,
neither indeed can be. Because the
carnal mind, hey, it's immity against
God. It hate God. That's why it do the
things that God don't like. But when you
walking in the spirit of God, then you
begin to do the things that God do like.
So what did Paul mean also when he was
saying that he died daily? Verse eight.
So then they that are in the flesh
cannot please God. Oh, so if you are
walking in that flesh, you cannot please
God. And our whole time on this earth is
supposed to be spent pleasing God. So
therefore, we have to die daily. Get rid
of the things of the flesh and serve God
with all thy heart. Verse nine. And
that's it.
But ye are not in the flesh, but in the
spirit. And so be that the spirit of God
dwell in you.
Now if any man have not the spirit of
Christ, he is none of his. He is none of
his. So you have to make sure that
you're doing your very best and putting
on that spirit of God and kill that
flesh every day if it tries to rise up
against you because it will certainly
kill you in the end if you don't get it
together. And that's all I
got. All right. We hope that answered
your question as we move on to our next
one. Moving on. Anthony Thomas says,
"Basis of
men. Explain Daniel 4 verse1 17." Daniel
4 and17 when it talks about the basis of
men. What you say about that, Julius?
Let's go there. Uh, brother
Tzdale, let's go there. Let's let's look
at what the uh what what the book says
about
this. When you get it, brother Daniel
4:17, read it.
This matter is by the decree of the
watchers and a demand by the word of the
holy one to the intent that the living
may know that the most high ruleth in
the kingdom of men and give it to
whosoever he will and setth up over it
the beast of men the best of men the
basis of men so uh this read the whole
chapter it's about Nebuchadnezzar's
pride uh and it goes back to Daniel the
third chapter You can read that on your
own where uh his pride lifted him up.
Even some looked upon him as a god.
Uh and the Lord want to teach
Nebuchadnezzar and the people throughout
all generations that he is the one that
rule everything and he set up whoever he
want to and take down whoever he want
to. Let's back this up with scripture.
This is what Nebuchadnezzar had to
learn. Let's go to uh Romans the 13th
chapter. Let's look let's deal with
this. Romans the 13th chapter and just
one verse. Romans 13 and1. And this what
from Nebuchadnezzar and from all rulers
back then even now today whoever's
president whoever is king everybody got
to learn this. Daniel 13:1 go ahead. You
said Daniel I'm sorry. Romans 13 and1.
Let every soul be subject unto the
higher power for there is no power but
of God. The powers that be are ordained
of God. And this what the world have to
understand. Now let's go back and let's
look at uh who these uh this matter is
by the decree of the watchers. These are
the
angels. But who is the real
decree? This is by the angels keep watch
sisters and brothers. Proverbs 15.
Proverbs
15. I got one place after this. Proverbs
15, my brother and three. These are the
watchers. Proverbs 15 and three. When
you get it to you, go ahead and read it.
The eyes of the Lord are in every place,
beholding the evil and the good. The
eyes of the Lord are his angels. In Job
the first and second chapters, the
angels came to give a report and Satan
came also. Where you been? Walking to
and fro in the earth and going up and
down. That's what the angels do. Now,
let's go back to uh Daniel chapter 4 and
close this
out. Daniel chapter
4 and read verse
17. Let's read it again. T go ahead.
This matter is by the decree of the
watchers and the demand by the word of
the holy ones to the intent that the
living may know that the most high
ruleth in the kingdom of men. Uh-huh.
And giveth it to whosoever he will, and
setth up over it the bases of men. Now
read verse uh 18. Go ahead quickly. This
dream I Nebuchadnezzar have seen. Now
there, O Belshazzar, declare the
interpretation thereof. For as much as
all the wise men of my kingdom are not
able to make known unto me the
interpretation, but thou art able, for
the spirit of the holy gods is in thee.
So nobody could explain Nebuchadnezzar
dream. He was the top man ran the whole
known uh world at that time. The first
gentile world ruler and he got high
minded and the Lord wanted to teach him
humility because pride and arrogancy
always come before the fall. So the Lord
wants to teach Nebuchadnezzar a lesson.
Let's look at verse 24 of 22 22.
It is thou, oh king, that are grown and
become strong, for thy greatness is
grown and reaches unto heaven and thy
dominion to the ends of the earth.
Because he was the first gentile world
ruler. Verse 24. Now we read where it
said this matter is by the decree of the
watchers. But who is behind the
watchers? Go ahead at verse 24.
This is the interpretation, oh king, and
this is the decree of the most high
which is come upon my lord the king. So
now after he knocked Nebuchadnezzar down
and for seven years made him walk out
there crawl like a beast covered with
feathers only one who knew him. Now he
found out after he after the seven years
read verse 34 and this what all the
leaders of the world have to find out.
Go ahead. And at the end of the days, I
Nebuchadnezzar lifted up my eyes unto
heaven, and my understanding returned
unto me. And I blessed the most high,
and I praise and honor him that liveth
forever, whose dominion is an
everlasting dominion, and his kingdom is
from generation to generation. See,
Nebuchadnezzar thought he was the one,
but God is the one. My last verse, verse
37. Finish his statement. Go ahead. Now
I Nebuchadnezzar praise and extol and
honor the king of heaven. All whose
works are true and his ways judgment.
And those that walk in pride he is able
to obease. So he is able to bring those
who are high and high minded and are
arrogant bring them down. And he'll put
anybody up who he wants to even the
lowest people. We'll take the people
that's low and not popular among the
people and put them up top and bring the
lofty and high-minded down. I apologize
about the long answer, but it's
necessary. That's all I got.
Okay. Lord say he hate pride. Right,
brother Julius? Hey, that's the number
one thing that he hate. Pride always
come before the fall. Yes, sir. All
right. Thank you for that. Hope that
answered that question. as we move on to
the next one. Moving on. Jennifer Love
says, "Trying to understand Genesis 32
verses 24- 28. Please help." All
right, brother Jerome, can you help
sister Jennifer here to understand that
Genesis 32 verse 24-28?
Let's go read
it. When you get it, Tanzania, go ahead.
And Jacob was left alone, and there
wrestled a man with him until the
breaking of the day. And when he saw
that he prevailed not against him, he
touched the hollow of his thigh. And the
hollow of Jacob's thigh was out of
joint, as he wrestled with him. And he
said, "Let me go, for the day breakth."
And he said, I would not let thee go
except thou bless me. And he said unto
him, What is thy name? And he said,
Jacob. And he said, "Thy name shall be
called no more Jacob, but Israel, for as
a prince prince has thou power with God
and with men, and has prevailed."
Okay, so uh the Lord uh sent an angel,
and a lot of people think it's a man,
but the Lord sent an angel uh because
the Lord wanted to adopt Jacob. So he
had the angel to ask Jacob, "What is
your name?" And he said, "My name is
Jacob." And uh the angel said your your
name shall no longer be Jacob but
Israel. Okay. So that was when the Lord
was adopting Jacob. That's why um um
Jacob is called Israel and that's why
his children are called the children of
Israel. The Lord has adopted the whole
nation. Okay. But uh let's go to Hosea
the 12th chapter so we can establish
that this was an in fact in fact an
angel. Okay. Hosea chapter 12 and pick
it up at verse three. Read to the
four. He took his brother by the heel in
the womb and by his strength he had
power with God. Yeah. He had power over
the angels and prevailed and he wept.
Okay.
Well, you can go ahead and finish it.
Okay. He wept and made supplication unto
him and he found him in Bethl and there
he spake with us. Okay. So, it say he
took his brother by the hill. Okay. You
talking about uh Jacob and Esau. Jacob
took Esau uh by the hill. Okay. So, we
talking about Jacob and Esau. But when
it came to this uh verse where it said
he had power with
God and with man, he had strength over
the
angel cuz there was an angel. That's who
he was wrestling with, an actual angel.
And that's who blessed. Okay, that's
that's all I got
on. You're on mute.
Thank you, brother. And we hope that our
sister got some understanding out of
that answer. All right, we're going to
move on to our next one. Sister Deborah.
Next one. Angela Clayton says, "In the
early days of time, it seems that group
of people were named after their
patriarchal lie. Ishelites, Amorites,
etc. From where does the name Hebrew
originate? And they give Genesis 14
verse13.
All right. So, brother Dre, can you
share some light on how the names came
about? Yes, sir. Let's go to uh Genesis
14 and read that 13th
verse. When you get it, go ahead,
Tanzel.
And there came one that had escaped and
told Abram the Hebrew, for he dwelt in
the plains of Mamry, an Amorite, brother
of Escal, and brother of Adner. And
these were confederates with Abram.
Okay, so we see it says Abraham the
Hebrew. And you want to know where he
got that from. But let's back up to uh
Genesis 10
now. Genesis
10. And we gonna
read
verse 20 and 21.
Go ahead, brother. When you get it.
These are the sons of Ham after their
families, after their tongues, in their
countries, and in their nations.
To Shem also, the father of all the
children of Eber, the brother of Japath,
the elder. Even to him were children
born. So Noah had three sons. He had
Shim, he had Ham, and he had [__] And
onto Shim was born Ebar. Ebar's name
means to cross over, just like Hebrew
means to cross over. So now, let's go
over to Philippians the third chapter.
Now, we going to look at somebody else
that was called Hebrew.
Philippians
3. And I want you to read verses 1 and
two. And we're going to
skip. Philippians
3 1 and two. Go ahead, brother. Finally,
my brethren, rejoice in the Lord. To
write the same thing to you. To me
indeed is not grievous, but for you it
is safe. Go ahead. And beware of dogs.
Beware of evil workers. Beware of
concision. So Paul is saying, "Beware of
the concision," which he talking about
the circumcision. But skip down to verse
four and go ahead.
Thought I might also have confidence in
the flesh. If if any other man thinkketh
that he have whereof he might trust in
the flesh, I more. Paul said, "Look, I
if man going to boast, I can boast more.
I more but go ahead. Circumcised the
eighth day of the stock of Israel of the
tribe of Benjamin and Hebrew of the
Hebrews as touching the law a Pharisee.
Notice Paul said, "I am a Hebrew of the
Hebrew." Because Hebrew just simply
means you come out of the land line of
Shim down from Shim to Ebar who Abraham
was the first that you read the name
Hebrew but it goes back to Ebar which
means to cross over. I hope that helped.
All right, brother. Thank you for that.
Hope that answered that question as we
move on to our next moving on. Cool Blue
asks, "Can you have intercourse with a
spouse and you all plan on marrying and
taking things
seriously?" Cool. Blue also want to know
what are the names of the books and
where can I get them? All right. I
assume when they talking about those
books, they mean history books. But um
we're going to ask the guest caller to
weigh in on these two questions.
Well, the first thing
is if you're not
married, then she is not your spouse.
Point blank. Right. And have an inner
court, you are
fornicating. Point blank.
As far as the books that the uh uh that
the Israeli
God uh sell uh uh that that was written
by the Israeli God like uh uh four winds
of heaven overview of the feast of the
Lord and dietary
law. Call the office of the Israeli God
and they will tell you not only the name
but how you going to get them. the
office of the Israeli God. The telephone
number is 708
3921320 78
1320 Okay.
All
right. Hope that that was of help to you
as we continue to move on to our next
question. Next question. Jennifer Love
asks, "Wasn't Jacob and
Rebecca deceitful when Jacob pretended
to be
Esau?" Genesis
27 11-14 is given. Genesis
27:11-14 with Jacob and Rebecca being
deceitful. Brother Jerome, shed some
light.
Let's go read it.
Genesis 27 11-14.
And Jacob said to Rebecca his mother,
"Behold, Esau, my brother, is a hairy
man. I am a smooth man, and my father
prevented will feel me, and I will sing
to him as a deceiver, and I shall bring
a curse upon me, and not a
blessing." And his mother said unto him,
"Upon me be thy curse, my son. only obey
my voice and go fetch me
them." And he went and fetched and
brought them to his mother. And his
mother made savory meat such as his
father
loved. Okay. I I know it's often said
that, you know,
uh Jacob was the one that was a surliner
and all of that and the deceiver. That's
that's what they say, but that's not
what the Bible say. Okay? It was
actually Esau that was being
deceitful. Why? Because he was supposed
to tell his father Isaac that he had
sold his birthight. He despised his
birthright. It didn't mean nothing to
him.
But most importantly, that was God's
intention from the
beginning for Jacob to get the birthight
because he said that elder which is
Esau shall serve the younger. All right?
And so to
keep Esau from stealing the birthright
that was legally Jacob's cuz he sold it
to him. His mother set this thing in
motion so
that Jacob can get the birthight that
was rightfully
his, legally his. Okay? And that's why
the Lord blessed it. He didn't curse it.
That's why his mother said, "Let the
curse be on me." Cuz he already she
already knew what God had told her about
the the two that was in her womb,
struggling in her womb. Right. All
right. So, now let's go to Genesis the
25th
chapter and we're going to read verse
19-
23. Genesis
25, 19-23.
Go ahead. And these are the generation
of Isaac, Abraham's son. Abraham begott
Isaac. And Isaac was 40 years old when
he took Rebecca to wife, the daughter of
Bethuel, the Syrian of Padamaram, the
sister of Leanne the Syrian. And Isaac
entreated the Lord for his wife because
she was barren. And the Lord was
entreated of him, and Rebecca his wife
conceived. Mhm. And the children
struggled together within her. And she
said, "If it be so, why am I thus, and
she went to inquire of the Lord?" What
the Lord say? Go ahead. When the And the
Lord said unto her, "Two nations are in
thy womb, and two manner of peoples
shall be separated from thy boughs. And
the one people shall be stronger than
the other people, and the elder shall
serve the younger." Mhm. And when her
days to be delivered were fulfilled,
behold, there were twins in her womb.
Skip down to verse 27, read to 34. And
the boys grew. And Esau was a cunning
hunter, a man of the field, and Jacob
was a plain man dwelling in tents. And
Isaac loved Esau because he did eat of
his venison. But Rebecca loved Jacob.
Mhm. And Jacob saw And Jacob saw
pottage. And Esau came from the fields,
and he was faint. And Esau said to
Jacob, "Feed me, I pray thee, with the
same red pottage, for I am faint."
Therefore was his name called Edom.
Uh-huh. And Jacob said, "Sell me this
day thy birthright." Jacob said, "Sell
me this day thy birthright." Go ahead.
And Esau said, "Behold, I am at the
point to die, and what profit shall this
birthright do to me?" It don't mean
nothing to him. Go ahead.
And Jacob said, "Swear to me this day."
And he swear unto him, and he sold his
birthight unto Jacob. Who whose
birthright is it is it now? Legally,
it's Jacob's. That's right. Not Esau.
All
right. Did you finish that 34? Now we're
at 34 now. Go ahead. Then Jacob gave
Esau bread and pottage of lentils and he
did eat and drink and rose up and went
his way. And Esau despised his
birthight.
Esau despised his birthright. All right.
But it was the Lord's intention for
Jacob to get the birthight anyway. And
he told Jacob's mother that the eldest
shall serve a younger. Jacob is the
younger. All right. So, uh, let's go
to Romans chapter 9. Romans chapter 9
and read verse 10
through13. When you get it, go ahead.
And not only this, but when Rebecca also
had conceived by one, even by our father
Isaac, for the children children being
not yet born, neither have he done any
good or evil, that the purpose of God
according to election might stand, not
of works, but of him that callth. It was
said unto her that the elder shall serve
the younger. As it is written, Jacob
have I love, but Esau have I hated.
said, "Jacob have I love, but Esau have
I hated." But back to the
point, the birthright belong to Jacob
legally. Okay. Now, if if I can, I I'm
going to quote this verse. We ain't got
to go there, but you can also go to
Hebrews the 12th chapter and ver read
verse 16 and 17. It's dealing with the
same subject matter. That's that's all I
got.
All right. So no fraud committed there.
It was a even exchange, wasn't it? Yes,
sir. All right, brother. Thank you for
that. And uh let us move on, sister
Deborah, to our next question. Moving
on. Jeffrey Meyers says, "If I'm alive
when Jesus comes, explain what grain I
shall transform into."
Corinthians is given without stating
book one or two and chapter. He only
gives verses 35 through 37. So please,
whoever answer this question, if you're
going to answer it, give the book and
the chapter so everyone will know. We
most certainly will. And we know our
brother Dre is going to shed some light
on that question and bring it to the
program. Go ahead, my brother. Yeah,
brother. You got you got a lot that's
kind of mixed up there because your
question says if I'm
alive when Jesus comes. Bear in mind you
saying if I'm alive when Jesus comes,
explain what grain I shall transform
into. and you quoting uh 1 Corinthians
15. So let's go there. But this is not
talking about if you are
alive. But let's let's read that. 1
Corinthians
35 to uh
37. Go ahead, brother.
But some man will say, "How are the dead
raised up? And with what body do they
come? We talking bodies and we talking
about the dead being raised up. Okay, go
ahead. Thou food that which thou seest
is not quickenth except it die.
And that which thou sest, thou seest not
that body that shall be but bear grain.
So he said that that body bears grain.
But that's a
metaphor because he's not talking about
you being some kind of grain or
something like that. Skip down to uh and
and read verse 38, man. Go ahead. But
God
giveth it a body as it have pleased him,
and to every seed his own body. So he's
talking bodies here. Now skip down to
verse 43 and 44 and read that.
It is sown in dishonor. It is raised in
glory. It is sown in weakness. It is
raised in power.
It is sown in natural body. It is raised
a spiritual body. Now talking you
talking about bodies here. When it's a
natural body, it is raised a spiritual
body. So we talking we not talking about
grain or wheats or tears or nothing like
that. So but you asked the question if
you are
alive when this happens. Let's go to uh
first Thessalonians 4. Now 1
Thessalonians
4 because your question says if I am
alive when Jesus comes explain so and
so. This is what happens if you are
alive when Jesus come and you make it.
First 1 Thessalonians 4 verse 15 and 16.
Go ahead, brother. But this we say unto
you by the word of the Lord, that we
which are alive and remain unto the
coming of the Lord shall not permit them
which are asleep. Go ahead. For the Lord
himself shall descend from heaven with a
shout, with the voice of the archangel,
and with the trump of God. And the dead
in Christ shall rise first. After the
dead in Christ rises first, what
happens? Go ahead. Then we which are
alive and remain shall be caught up
together with them in the clouds to meet
the Lord in the air. And so shall we
ever be with the Lord. If you are alive
at this time and you be so blessed to
make it, you will meet the Lord in the
air and you don't just live there. You
can read Zechariah 14 1-5 and it'll tell
you where you coming to on your own. I
hope that help.
All right. Yes, sir. And anybody that's
not alive, if you got that good report
card, you'll be in good shape, won't
you? Yes, sir. Uhhuh. Yes, indeed. All
right. Hope that answers your question
there, brother. As we move on to our
next next one, Edward Barber asks, "How
do we rebuke others who er in scriptures
and what kind of mindset should we be in
doing it?" He also wants to know, "What
is free grace?"
All right, there's a lot of people that
air in scripture. Let's start there.
Just call her please.
Okay. The first thing is how to rebuke a
person. Let's go into second Timothy the
4th chapter and read verse two.
Preach the word. Be instant in season,
out of season. Reprove, rebuke, exhort
with all longsuffering and doctrine.
So what you do is you sit down there and
you open that book and say, "Let's go in
the Bible and have a look at it cuz
you're wrong." And I'm going to show you
why. And you don't have to be angry at
doing it. Go to Psalms 6 and read verse
one.
Psalm 6 and verse one.
Oh Lord, rebuke me not in thy anger,
neither chasen me in thy hot
displeasure.
So what you do is you cut you you do
what we request the Lord want to do when
we are wrong. If we need rebuking, we
don't want the Lord to rebuke us in
anger and and and and
out and mean. What you do is you sit
down with a nice pleasant
attitude
[Music]
and with some respect and show them what
they are wrong in the Bible just like
second Timothy is. And the second part
was is uh uh um
what is free grace? What is free grace?
Well, the whole thing is uh grace itself
mean a free gift. Let's go to Romans the
5th chapter, read 15 to 18. Then we're
going to skip
down to 21. So when you get it, go
ahead.
Romans 5, pick it up at 15.
But now as the offense, so also is the
free gift. For for if though the offense
of one many be dead, much more the grace
of God, and the gift by grace, which is
by one man, Jesus Christ, have abound
unto
many. And now, as it was by one that
sin, so is the gift. For the judgment
was by one to condemnation, but the free
gift is of many offenses unto
justification.
For if by one man offense death reign by
one, much more they which receive
abundance of grace and of the gift of
righteousness shall reign in life by one
Jesus
Christ. So therefore, what verse is
that? Now that was the end of 17.
Go ahead. Therefore, as by the offense
of one judgment came upon all men to
condemnation, even so by the
righteousness of one, the free gift came
upon all men unto justification of
life. And as by one man disobedience,
many were made sinners, so by the
obedience of one shall many be made
righteous.
Mhm.
Now, what verse was that? That was the
end of 19.
Read verse 21.
That as sin have reigned unto death,
even so might grace reign through
righteousness unto eternal life by Jesus
Christ our Lord.
Look what happened to man sin against
God. And the one man was Adam and he
brought death into the creation. But
then Jesus came and he reversed it by
dying on the
cross. And he gave uh uh man another
shot at becoming immortal immortal and
God. Skip let's go to Psalm 69 and read
verse 4. 69 and
4.
Psalm
69 and four and verse four.
They that hate me without a cause are
more than the hairs of my head. They
that would destroy me, being my enemies
wrongfully are mighty. Then I restore
that which I took not away.
So now that's Jesus talking by the mouth
of David.
But what happened is Adam took away your
immortality and Jesus
came and gave it back. Right? And you
didn't do nothing. Man didn't do nothing
to receive that gift. Therefore, it was
grace. It was a free
gift. That's all I have to say.
Yes, sir. We thank God for that free
gift. Absolutely. Yes, sir. All right. I
hope that answered your question as we
move on to our next one. Next one. Most
love warns you to explain Ephesians 6
verse 12. Does that mean spirits are
walking among us? Like, can there be one
inside your house? I don't want to call
it a ghost.
All right. So, brother Julius, a little
light on that. Ephesians 6 and2 for
starters. Let's go to uh Brother Tangel,
let's go
there.
And ghost is another slang word for
spirit. So, you don't have to call it if
you don't want to. It does not it does
not take away from what it is. You know,
like the Holy Ghost or the Holy Spirit.
In this case, in this context, these are
angels. holy
angels and you got unholy angels which
are we call
demons. Uh Ephesians 6. This time we
going to read verse 11. We going to
start at verse 11 because when you read
the book of Revelation on your own, read
Revelation uh 127. There was war in
heaven. Satan and his angels got kicked
out into the earth. So the earth is
their uh domain right now. That's where
they be. All these fallen unseen evil
angels, you cannot see them, but they
are but they exist when you get it. Re
Ephesians 6 and 11. Go ahead. Put on the
whole armor of God able to stand against
the ws of the devil. So you got to
stand. That mean that in order to stand
against uh oppose something, it has to
be it has to exist and it has to be
here. Go ahead. But be wrestled not
against flesh and blood, but against
principalities, against powers, against
the rulers of the darkness of this
world. Uhhuh. Spirit your wickedness in
high places. Go ahead.
Wherefore take unto you the whole armor
of God, that you may be able to
withstand in the evil day, and having
done all to stand. No, because we are
wrestling against uh unseen powers,
against the rulers of the darkness of
this world. These evil angels that you
cannot see, but they are here. They are
here. Let me show you that they're here.
Job chapter
one. Job chapter 1. And when you get it,
brother, read verse six. Read verse six.
Now there was a day when the sons of God
came to present themselves before the
Lord, and Satan came also among them.
Now these sons of God are the holy
angels that didn't uh ride along with
Satan. These are the holy angels. Go
ahead. And the Lord said unto Satan,
"Whence comest thou?" Then Satan
answered the Lord and said, "From going
to and fro in in the earth, and from
walking up and down in it." So now they
are here and yes they can be in your
house because they will come in your
house and you can conjure them up and
uh they can also whoop you too. Let's go
and look at some people who uh fought
against and vexed the Holy Spirit. Let's
go to
Acts chapter
5. Acts chapter 5. A wonderful example
that these beings are
here. You don't have to call it ghosts,
but he say he calls his angels
spirits.
Acts 5
1-3. When you get go ahead to a certain
man named Ananas with Safar, his wife
sold a possession and kept kept back
part of the price. His wife also being
privy to it and brought a certain part
and laid it at the apostles feet. So now
there was a a a big outpouring of the
spirit and the people was compelled to
bring everything and and sold lands and
stuff so that the church was growing so
that everybody can have everything in
common. Ananas and Safirus made a vow
and they kept back part uh they sold
some property or whatever they had and
they kept back they sold it and kept
back part of the price of it instead of
uh giving uh everything that they were
supposed to give. Go ahead. But Peter
said, "Ananas, why hast Satan filled thy
heart to lie to the Holy Ghost?" Why has
who? Satan. Oh, you mean that same Satan
that's walking to and from the earth
with his angels? Yes. Because they're
here. Now, where is he at? Continue to
read. And to keep back part of the price
of the land. Uh-huh. While it remainers,
was it not thy own? Uh-huh. And after it
was sold, was it not thy own power? Why
hast thou conceived this thing in thy
heart? Yeah.
Not go ahead. Not lied unto men, but
unto God.
Go ahead. And Ananas hearing these words
fell down and gave up the ghost. And
great fear came on all them that heard
these things. So they died. So he died
on the spot. He he died on the on the
spot. Now, let's go to uh skip down.
Let's see here. Skip down to verse uh
when his wife pick it up at verse eight.
Uh verse seven. Go ahead. And it was
about the space of three hours after
when his wife not knowing what was done
came in. And Peter answered unto her,
"Tell me whether you sold the lamb for
so much." And she said, "Yeah, for so
much." Uh-huh. And Peter said unto her,
"How is it that ye have agreed together
to tempt the spirit of the Lord?" That's
the
angel. Because the eyes of the Lord, as
we read earlier in Proverbs 15:3, are in
all places beholding the evil and the
good. Go ahead.
Behold, the feet of them which have
buried thy husband are at the door.
I the door where evidently the door of
their house. Go ahead.
Then fell she down straight way at his
feet and yielded up the ghost. And the
young man came in and found her dead and
carrying her for bearing her by her
husband. So
now in your house they could be in your
house listening, watching just like
Satan the devil walketh about seeking
whom he may devour. The book said in
Peter, first Peter, be sober, be
viligent, for your adversary, the devil,
walketh about seeking whom he may
devour. All you got to do is give him
the opportunity. He will come in and
wreak havoc in you and even uh cause you
to die because of your behavior and the
thing that come out of your mouth.
That's all I got. I hope that helps. So,
yes, we entertain uh uh uh uh angels
unaware. We can read that to you. Mhm.
You want to read that, brother Julius?
Yeah, we got the time if if uh if we can
uh read that. Where is that at? Uh it's
in uh it's going to be in that Hebrews
13 and verse two. I think that's I got
that written to it. First John 1. What
is it, Drea? First John 4:1. If it's not
Hebrews, if that's not the one you
talking about. Let me see. First John 4.
No, no, no. It's Hebrews. It's Hebrews.
Okay. Hebrews. Hebrews 13:22. Like
Cornell said, read it. Hebrews 13:2,
"Be not forgetful to entertain
strangers, but thereby some have
entertained angels unawares." And so,
yes, the angels are among us, and they
can be in your house or they can be in
your car. You know, uh they're already
in the
church. So, that's the answer to that. I
hope that helped. All right, thank you
for that, brother. As we move on to our
next question with a time check. Yes,
the time is
8:21. Tasha Adams asks, "Who took the
place of UK, which is the United Kingdom
in the EU, the European Union to fulfill
the 10." All right, why don't we open
that question up to the
panel and
um maybe the the guest caller would like
to start off on that one on who took the
place of the UK in the EU to fulfill the
10.
Well, the problem
is the UK is still on the books, right?
And until they are taken off the
books, we don't know who going to take
their
place. They are part of the contract.
They they signed the uh the contract
which is called the treat the treaties
which is called the treaties of Rome and
their name is still on it and can't
nobody else get them until they remove
their name.
So truth of the matter is reality is
still there.
Yep.
All right. Thank you for that and we
hope that that answers your question as
we move on. Moving on. Barbara still
please stay fully next time in your
questions what you are asking. You say,
"How come they didn't say by no other
name can you be saved?"
All right. Um had a conversation uh with
a lady about this and she was speaking
in terms of all the different names out
here and they want to know what name to
lock in on. How come that scripture is
not read about, you know, by no other
name can you be saved? So, let's go into
that Acts 4 and let's read
that. Let's read that in. Acts four and
let's pick it up at 10 and show that we
bringing in Jesus here.
Acts 4 and 10. Go ahead, brother. be it
known unto you all and to all the people
of Israel. That by the name of Jesus
Christ of Nazareth, whom ye crucified,
whom God raised from the dead, even by
him doeth this man stand here before you
hold. So we see that it was Jesus of
Nazareth who was crucified. Go ahead.
11. This is the stone which was set at
not of you builders which has become the
head of the corner. Yeah, he was really
set as no big deal amongst the builders
but he is the head of the corner.
However you choose to live your life,
you will see him at the end of the road.
Go ahead, brother. Neither is there
salvation in any other. For there is
none other name under heaven given among
men whereby we must be saved. All right.
So that is where the scripture is
located for that Barbara. So let's go
into Matthews right quick and read a
little bit more about that powerful
name. Matthew 1 and let's see. Even
though the father sent his son to come
and die for the sins of the world, he
was crucified. The same Jesus of
Nazareth. Matthew 1 and let's read that
verse 18 and let's see his birth and
then let's see his
mission Matthew
18 and one 18 go ahead I'm sorry 1 and
18 now the birth of Jesus Christ was on
this
wise when as his mother Mary was
expoused to Joseph before they came
together she was fired with child of the
Holy Ghost. All right. So, we see that
Jesus, the angel, brought the message to
Mary, saying that she was going to have
a son and his name was Jesus because the
father sent him to come and die for the
sins of the world. And it says before
they came together. So, Joseph played no
part in that. She was still a virgin and
she had a baby while she was still a
virgin. Skip down and let's see what his
mission was in verse 21. Go ahead. And
she shall bring forth a son, and thou
shalt call his name Jesus. Uhhuh. He
shall save his people from their sins.
Yes. And he came to die for the sins of
the whole world. One more place.
Philippians. Philippians
2. Because this the is the only God that
can save, that can kill and make alive,
that can wound and can heal.
Philippians the 2 chapter. So when you
get there, brother, pick it up at that
verse
uh five and then we're gonna do a little
skipping
there. Go ahead. Let this mind be in you
which was also in Christ Jesus. Yes. Who
being in the form of God in that robbery
to be equal with God? No. Because he
came from the Godhead. He was sent. Skip
down to verse
uh keep read. Go ahead.
But made himself of no reputation and
took upon him the form of a servant and
was made in the likeness of
man. And being found in fashion as a
man, he humbled himself and became
obedient unto death, even the death of
the cross. And this is the same Jesus
that we heard that he became of no
reputation. He humbled himself and came
and died for the sins and was obedient
even unto death. Go ahead, brother.
Yeah, go ahead. Read.
Wherefore God also have highly exalted
him and given him a name which is above
every name. which is above every name.
That's why we read earlier that that was
the only name which is Jesus whereby men
must be saved. And what are they going
to do before this king here? Go ahead.
That at the name of Jesus, every knee
should bow of things in heaven and
things in earth and things under the
earth. Uhhuh. And that every tongue
should confess that Jesus Christ is Lord
to the glory of God the Father. Yes sir.
So that is a very powerful name and
every knee bow to it. And that son who
came and died for all of our sins like
the guest caller said it gave us a free
shot again at that everlasting life.
Right. So that's all I got on
that and we're going to move on to our
next question. Yes. Moving on.
Orlando Davyy uh says in um Acts 15
verse 7 and verse 12, Peter declared
that by his mouth the Gentiles should
hear the gospel and believe. But in Acts
26 verse 15 and verse 17, Paul was sent
to the Gentiles. Please share some
light. All right, Orlando, here comes
some light here. Let's go to that Acts
15, brother Tanzel. Acts 15, pick it up
at verse 7. And the guest caller will
share some light from there.
Acts 15 and
7. And when there had been much
disputing, Peter rose up and said unto
them, "Men and brethren, ye know how
that a good while ago God made choice
among us, that the Gentiles by my mouth
should hear the word of the gospel and
believe." Mhm.
Now, that was verse seven, right? Right.
Yep.
And read verse 12 first. Next.
Verse 12. Then all the multitude kept
silence and gave audience to Barnabas
and Paul declaring what miracles and
wonders God had wrought among the
Gentiles by them.
Okay? Because he said seven and verse
12. I want to do 12 first. All it's
saying is everybody got quiet and let
Barnabas and Paul make their case. But
now when we come up on verse seven, even
though Paul was was uh designated by God
as the uh apostle to the Gentiles, Peter
was the one that the Lord left the keys
to. Therefore, Peter was the first that
brought the word to the Gentiles. Go to
Acts the 10th chapter, read 1-6, and
we're going to do some skipping.
There was a certain man in Queseria
called Cornelius, a centurion of the
band called the Italian band, a devout
man, and one that feared God with all
his house, which gave much arms to the
people, and prayed to God
always. And he saw in a vision evidently
about the ninth hour of the day, an
angel of God coming into him, and saying
unto him, Cornelius. And when he looked
on him, he was afraid, and said, What is
it, Lord? And he said unto him, "Thy
prayers and thy arms are come up for a
memorial before God. And now send men to
Japa, and call for one Simon, whose
surname is Peter. He lodged with one
Simon a tanner, whose house is by the
seaside. He shall tell thee what thou
artest to do."
So now the Lord, the angel told uh
uh first gentile brought into the church
under the new covenant to go and find
Peter and he will tell you what to do.
So he sent Peter and they found Peter
and then the his servants brought Peter
to Cornelia's house. Skip down to verse
25 and we're going to read from 25 to
28.
And as Peter was coming in, Cornelius
met him and fell down at his feet and
worshiped him. But Peter took him up,
saying, "Stand up. I myself also am a
man." And as he talked with them, he
went in and found many that were come
together. And he said unto them, "Ye
know how that it is an unlawful thing
for a man that is a Jew to keep company
or come unto one of another nation. But
God have showed me that I should not
call any man common or unclean.
So now that let you know that uh Peter
made it clear that it was it was
unlawful for a man to come into any
other nation because Jesus had already
declared that in the 10th chapter of
Matthews when he told them that go not
in the way of the Gentiles neither to
Samaria but go rather to the lost sheep
of Israel. But when Peter got through
having that
dream and the Lord showed him that he
was about to bring because he had to
prepare him to bring Gentiles into the
church. So once he told him that then he
started to teach him. Read verse 34.
Then Peter opened his mouth and said,
"Of a truth, I perceive that God has no
respect of person, but in every nation,
he that fear of him and work of
righteousness is accepted with him."
Yep.
So that's why Peter said by his mouth
the gentile was brought in because he is
the one that brought the first set of
Gentiles into the
church under new covenant and later on
the Lord called
Paul and he con converted him and he
made him apostles to the gentile but
Peter was the first. That's all I have
to say.
All right, we hope that that shed the
light that you was looking
for.
Um, and we're going to move on to our
next question. Next question. Be alert
as when Jesus returns together Israel,
will there be a war going on during the
gathering?
Will there be a war going on when Jesus
returns to gather Israel? Guess caller.
Will there
and will there be a war going on uh uh
uh during the gathering? No. No. So the
Lord's going to come and if a war of
Armageddon, he going to take this earth
down. And once he take the earth down,
then ain't going to be no more war. But
after Israel is back in the land, there
will be two more attempts to make war.
And the Lord going to deal with those.
Let's show you. Let's go first to
Ezekiel 38th
chapter and we're going to start
reading. We're going to read verses
1-4. Let me know you read four and then
we're going to go to 21 and 22. Let me
know when you finish 4 and go and then
we'll go to 21 and 22. Read it. And the
word of the Lord came unto me, saying,
Son of man, set thy face against God,
the land of Magog, the chief prince of
Meek and Tubal, and prophesies against
him, and say, thus sayeth the Lord God,
behold, I am against thee, oh God, the
chief prince of Mack and Tubal. And I
will turn thee back and put hooks in thy
jaw. And I will bring thee forth and all
thy armies, horses and horsemen, all of
them clothed with all sorts of armor,
even a great company with bucklers and
shields, all of them handling
swords. That was the end of verse four.
Skip down and read verse 21 and 22.
And I will call for a sword against them
throughout all my mouth, said the Lord
God. Every man's sword shall be against
his brother. And I will plead against
him with pestilence and with blood. And
I will rain upon him and upon his bands
and upon the many people that are with
him and overflowing rain and great
hailstone fives and brimstone.
So when they attempt come up to try and
attempt attack Israel once they've been
back once they were back in the land
then the Lord is going to turn the
swords everybody on themselves and then
he going to deal with killing with rain
and hail storms. That's and so skip down
and then now let's go to Ezekiel the
39th 9th chapter and read verse 1-4 cuz
this is the same time 39 1-4 dealing
with Gog and Magog which is
Russia. Go ahead. Therefore thou son of
man prophesied against God and say thus
sayeth the Lord God. Behold I am against
thee, oh God, the chief prince of Mach
and Tabal. And I will turn thee back and
leave but the sixth part of thee and
will cause thee to come up from the
north part and will bring thee upon the
mountains of Israel. I will smite thy
bow out of thy left hand and will cause
thy arrows to fall out of thy right
hand. Thou shalt fall upon the mountains
of Israel, thou and all thy bands, and
the people that is with thee. I will
give thee unto the ravenest birds of
every sort, and to the beast to the
fields to be devoured.
Now, that's the first attempt at
battle where they going to attempt to
attack Israel. So the Lord's going to
bring Gog up, which is which is Russia,
like I said, and he's going to kill the
whole
army and uh uh he going to leave only a
tent part of Gogg left. That's the first
attempt. Now, let's show you when the
second attempt is going to be made.
Let's go into Revelation the 20th
chapter, and we're going to read verse
4, and then we're going to skip down and
read verses 7-9.
And I saw a throne, and they that sat
upon them, and judgment was given unto
them. And I saw the souls of them that
were beheaded for the witness of Jesus,
and for the word of God, and which had
not worshiped the beast, neither his
image, neither had received his mark
upon their forehead or in their hands.
And they lived and reigned with Christ a
thousand years.
Now, this is during the millennium
period. He did not go off.
Now, he going to rule this earth for a
thousand years. And let's see what's
going to happen when the thousand years
is over with. Skip down to verse 7. Read
7-9.
And when the thousand years are expired,
Satan shall be loosed out of his prison,
and shall go out to deceive the nations
which are in the four quarters of the
earth, Gog and Magog, to gather them
together to battle, the number of whom
is as the sand of the sea.
And they went up on the breath of the
earth and compassed the camp of the
saints
about and the beloved city and fire came
down from God out of heaven and devoured
them.
So now he using uh uh uh Russia because
he he will have put the beast in the
false prophet in the lake of fire. So at
the end of the thousand years he going
to lose Satan. Satan going to get Russia
and they going to and and Satan going to
uh have so many people following him
it's going to be like the sands of the
sea. So they going to go up on the
breath of the earth and they're going to
surround the camp of the saints but then
fire going to come down from the father
and kill them and then Satan going cast
into the lake of fire and then you going
to have the white throne judgment.
There's no more walls. The last war they
had was the war of
Armageddon. And then once Israel came
back, they attempted war, but God made
short short work of them. And after the
thousand years uh uh of rule that Jesus
going to rule this earth, Satan going to
be loosed and they going to try to
assault the camp of the saints again.
And the father going to rain down fire
and kill them all. So ain't no walls
during the uh uh uh rule. is going to be
two attempts. One before and one after
the mill after the thousand years of
peace. That's all I have to say.
Yep. And I believe too, guest caller, we
got a lesson on that called the last
three battles.
That's correct.
All right. Thank you for that. We hope
that answered your question. Sister
Deborah, is it time to go into new
territory? Yes, it's time. Uh we are now
into tonight's Q&A for Wednesday, April
the 16,
2025. Sai Amaru Israel asks, "Should
children who have not have been baptized
or reached the age of 20 partake in
Passover given the requirements of
selfexamination?"
uh they give 1 Corinians
11 27- 29.
All right. 1 Corinthians 11 27-
29. And um like for the guest caller to
weigh in on this about uh children being
baptized
um take part in the Passover.
Let's go there to that 1 Corinthians 11
and pick it up at that verse
27.
Okay. Wherefore whosoever shall eat this
bread and drink this cup of the Lord
unworthily shall be guilty of the body
and blood of the Lord. But let a man
examine himself and so let him eat of
that bread and drink of that cup. For he
that eateth and drinkketh unworthily
eateth and drinkketh damnation to
himself, not discerning the Lord's
body. Well, the whole thing is the word
unworthy. That covers a whole lot of
area. But if you want to have a
specific, then the Lord declared who
should not take the Passover. That's in
Exodus 12 chapter. Let's uh
uh let's get right down to it. Who can
somebody can find it right quick? I know
in Exodus who cannot take the Passover
40 starting at 43.
Mhm.
The ordinance of the Passover. Yeah.
10 Exodus 12 and let's pick it up at
that 43. by brother Tracy.
And the Lord said unto Moses and Aaron,
"This is the ordinance of the Passover.
There should no stranger eat thereof.
But every man's servant that is bought
for money, when thou hast circumcised
him, then shall he eat
thereof. A foreigner and hire servant
shall not eat thereof."
Now skip down and read 48.
And when a stranger shall sjourn with
thee, and will keep the Passover to the
Lord, let all his males be
circumcised, and then let him come near
and keep it, and he shall be as one that
is born in the land. For no
uncircumcised person shall eat
thereof, one law shall be to him that is
homeborn, and unto the stranger that
sjourneth among you.
So now when you when you start talking
about unworthy, I understand was written
in Corinthians, but that word covers a
whole lot of
area. So the if so the only specific
statement we have is if you're not
circumcised, you can't take the
Passover.
Yes, caller. Can we go to Luke?
Go ahead. Can we go to Luke the second
chapter? Cornell Luke. Uh I'm sorry.
Tanzania Luke chapter
2 and let's pick this up at verse
40. And when you get it, go ahead and
read it. Luke 2 and 40.
And the child grew and waxed strong in
spirit, filled with wisdom, and the
grace of God was upon him. Go ahead. Now
his parents went to Jerusalem every year
at the feast of the Passover. At the
feast of the Passover, who was with him?
Go ahead. And when he was 12 years old,
they went out to Jerusalem after the
custom to the feast. And they kept uh Go
ahead. 43.
And when they had fulfilled the days as
they returned, the child Jesus terried
behind in Jerusalem, and Joseph and his
mother knew not of it. So Jesus kept the
Passover at 12 years old and the feast
of unleven bread because and he was
circumcised at 8 days old but he met he
met the
criteria and the books ain't a child in
the way that they should go.
Yeah. So, and and then that question too
with them talking about should children
who have not been baptized yet and they
under the age of 20, can they partake in
the
Passover? You know, being that they have
not been, you know, that they under 20.
But if you have they aren't circumcised,
under 20 or not, still cannot partake in
the Passover according to what we just
read.
Well, the circumcision is what the Lord
give to prohibit you from taking it.
Yep. Whatever age.
That's right. Whatever age you might be.
So, all right. We hope that that
answered your question there. Now, this
next question almost went into our do
not answer poll because it's got a whole
lot in it. I mean, you made it a long
question and we don't have time because
we try and spread it evenly. And this
falls in the category of long scripture
question, but we asked our sister
Deborah out of our kindness to please
shorten it so we could shed some light
best we can on this question. So next
time please shorten it up or we might
not answer it. Sister De. Yes. Cassie
Lee says, "Since angels spirits can
neither marry nor have children, then
was Adam and Eve gods in the beginning?"
And the other question will be also Adam
didn't name Eve until they were driven
out of the garden of Eden which mean the
mother of the living. Am I understanding
this correctly?
All right, let's open that up to the
panel and
go ahead guest call. The first part
first. So the first part was
again she states since a uh since angel
spirits can neither marry nor have
children then was Adam and Eve
gods in the beginning.
Go to go to Genesis the 2
chapter and read verse 7.
The Lord God formed man of the dust of
the ground and breathe into his nostril
the breath of life and man became a
living
soul. So how could man be God and he was
dug out of the ground? Can't be before
you
make. So no, Adam and Eve wasn't God.
Ain't got nothing to do with the angels
married or giving in
marriage. And what's the second part?
And also, Adam didn't name Eve until
they were driven out of the Garden of
Eden, which means the mother of the
living. Am I understanding this
correctly? So, Adam did name Eve until
they were driven out of the Garden of
Eden.
Well, the Bible stated that he named
uh sometime uh the name could have been
before. So, we can't really say
that. But if you want to, you can go
read the scripture and see what it
said. Did she give any scripture on it?
No.
If we can find
it. Okay. Funny.
Say that again, brother. Uh, Genesis 3
and 20. Yep, that would be correct.
Let's go there. Genesis 3 and and 20.
And Adam called his wife named Eve
because she was the mother of all
living.
That's three and
20. Yep.
All they say he called his wife name Eve
and she was the mother of of you know
because she is the mother of all living.
Now he could have called that before or
after they move out of the out of was
driven out of the garden. The scripture
don't really say.
Yep. So we'll have to leave that
question right there as sister Devil
gives us a time check cuz time is
ticking. And let's open the next
question up to the panel. Go ahead.
Right. Okay. The time is 8:15. Uh 8:50.
She also asks, "In the New Testament, is
the Gospel according to John the same
person who wrote the first and second
letters to the churches?" Because I
thought he was beheaded by King Herod.
That was John. That was John the Baptist
that was beheaded. The Apostle John
wrote first John, second John, Third
John and wrote Revelation.
Yeah. John was written by the Apostle
John.
Herod be John the Baptist.
Guess call him. Oh, he right. Two
different John. John the Baptist. Right.
He came uh uh uh uh you know, he came
before he was born before Jesus. He's
the one that baptized people. And John
wrote uh uh
uh
Revelation and wrote uh first and
second, third John is the same
John. Two different Johns all together.
Mhm. And he wrote the Gospel of John.
Yeah. Say that again, Julius. The the
the the Gospel of John was written by uh
the Apostle John. He also wrote First
John, 2 John, Third John, and the book
of Revelation.
Indeed. Not John the Baptist. No. No.
John the Baptist was just coming to lead
the way for the one that was coming
after him, which was Jesus. There you
go. All right, brother. Thank you for
that good light. As we move on to our
next one, moving on. De Chenet Love It
says, "I was in a live Tik Tok and this
is more so for clarification.
These people tried to say that Jesus was
a son because of the verse that had the
name bar Jesus which spoke of a false
prophet. Can you clarify that verse so I
can educate some people? And they give
she gives Acts 13 verses 6-8.
Acts
13 verses 6-8.
Yes. All right. Let's go there and then
we'll open it up to the panel at Acts.
And uh when you get there, Brother
Tanzel. Acts 13 6 through 8. Go ahead,
brother. And when they had gone through
the aisles unto
Papos, they found a certain sorceress, a
false prophet, a Jew who names was Bar
Jesus, which was what the deputy of the
country, Sergius Paulus, a prudent man
who called for Barnabas and Saul and
desired to hear the word of
God. One one more verse. But alignments
but alignments the sorcerer for so is
his name by interpretation withtood them
seeking to turn away the deputy from the
faith.
All right and that question again
Deborah
uh she states these people tried to say
that Jesus had a son because of the
verse that had the name bar Jesus which
spoke of a a false prophet. So they want
to give some clarification of that
scripture. Acts 13 6-8.
Yeah. Now Jesus did not have a son but
open to the panel.
The whole thing is the name bar Jesus.
That's somebody if you read that show
you that this guy tried to keep them
away from the leader there.
Jesus mean to somebody try to keep them
from being taught about Jesus. Ain't got
nothing to do with no son. No, not at
all.
Yeah.
Then Jesus died at 33 years.
How could he have a old man that's going
to be called his son?
Yeah. Who who is a sorcerer and a false
prophet.
There you go. Come on. Give me a break.
Yeah. Yeah. Give us all the break.
All right. Thank you for that. And uh
Sister Deborah, our next question. Next
question. Ran
64 asks in Galatians 2 verse 16 where it
says, "Man is not justified by the works
of the law." What does this mean
overall, especially dealing with the
law?
All right, let's go to uh Galatians 2
and uh panel, we're going
to join in on that. Go ahead, Tanzel.
Galatians 2 and 16.
Knowing that a man is not justified by
the works of the law, but by the faith
of Jesus Christ, even we have believed
in Jesus Christ, that we might be
justified by the faith of Christ, and
not by the works of the law. For by the
works of the law shall no flesh be
justified.
Let's go and show you what that mean. Go
into Hebrews the 10th chapter and read
verse one. Yes, sir.
For the law having a shadow of good
things to come, and not the very image
of the things, can never with those
sacrifice, which they offer year by
year, continually make the comers there
unto perfect.
Why couldn't they? Skip down to verse
four and continue. For it is not
possible that the blood of bulls and of
goats should take away sin.
Now that's the reason why because that
law is the law of animal
sacrifice not talking about God
commandments. So killing animals could
not take away sin. That's why Jesus
needed a body to die. Read read verse
five.
Wherefore when he cometh unto the world,
he said, "Sacrifice and offer you, thou
wouldest not, but a body thou hast
prepared
me." Now, what did he need with that
body? Skip down to verse 10 and read it.
By the which will we are sanctified
through the offering of the body of
Jesus Christ once for all.
Now, keep reading. Read some more. But
every priest stand of daily ministry and
offering often times the same sacrifices
which can never take away sins.
[Music]
But this man after he had offered one
sacrifice for sins forever sat down on
the right hand of God from henceforth
expecting expecting till his enemies be
made his
foottool. For by one offering he had
perfected forever them that are
sanctified. Whereof the Holy Ghost also
is a witness to us. For after that he
had said
before. This is the covenant that I will
make with them after those days said the
Lord. I will put my laws into their
hearts and in their minds will I write
them and their sins. How is it now? How
is it that he going to terminate the law
when he turn around and say he going to
write his laws in your heart and in your
mind. Right. Right. Because you have two
sets of
laws. Now the one is going to write in
your mind that is the one that you have
to believe and walk in to get salvation.
Come on. Let's go into Matthew the 19th
chapter and somebody start where the man
asked Jesus what he have to do to get
eternal life.
[Music]
Uh, you want to pick it up where you
call him good master, right? Or do you
want to go into uh Oh, okay. Verse verse
16. Yeah. 16.
And behold, one came and said unto him,
Good Master, what good thing shall I do
that I may have eternal life? And he
said unto him, Why call thou me good?
There is none good but one, that is God.
But if thou will enter into life, keep
the commandments.
Point blank.
That's it. Yeah.
through the law it can't help you. It
was the law of animal sacrifice because
it can't take away sin. But like Jesus
told that asked him what to do to get
eternal life. He simply told him keep
the commandments. That is the law.
We go to a whole lot of we that's
enough. That's all I have to say. All
right. So, Sister Devil, let's do one
more question and that will be the end
of the program. Yeah, the time is 900
PM.
Oh, time is 900 p.m. Okay. Time fly when
you're having fun. So, we have come to
the end of the program and we'd like to
thank everybody from all around the
world who joined us this evening and
we'd like to say if you sent in a
question and we didn't get to it, please
don't resubmit it. Sister Deborah, take
it, put it in rotation, and we will
address that question next Wednesday.
So, we thank you all again, and until we
come together again, be safe, be
blessed, stay prayed up, and may the
Lord have mercy on us all as our brother
Tanzel closes us out. Our Father, which
are in heaven, hallowed be thy name. Thy
kingdom come, thy will be done in earth
as it is in heaven. Give us this day our
daily bread, and forgive us of our debts
as we forgive our debtors, and lead us
not into temptation, but deliver us from
evil. For thine is the kingdom, and the
power, and the glory forever. In Jesus
name we